Lluis Artus | Dr.

Harald Løvenskiolds vei 4 – 0760 Oslo – Norway

Born: 16th of December, 1992

☑ Ilartuss7@gmail.comin Iluis-artus-suarez※ Ilartuss7¶ GitHub¶ V0c1H8IAAAAJ

https://lluisartussuarez.github.io/



Personal Statement

PhD in computational chemistry, specializing in the simulation of catalytic systems. I have been studying CO_2 hydrogenation mechanisms for seven years and enantioselective hydrogenation of olefins for two years. Using density functional theory, classical molecular dynamics, and microkinetic modeling, I can study the role of catalysts in the reactions. That information is essential to identify favorable and detrimental factors that determine the reaction rates and allow the development of faster and more stable catalysts.

Machine learning applied to theoretical chemistry is rising in popularity. Therefore, last year, I started training myself in it. I have been reading about state-of-the-art ML techniques, attending an ML conference applied to computational chemistry, and, in November 2023, enrolling in IBM's online course on Machine Learning. There, I learned about exploratory data analysis, regression, classification, and unsupervised models, but it will also cover genetic models and deep learning. I look forward to implementing what I learned into a practical application.

Professional experience

— Professional experience	
Science	
NCMM Norwegian Centre for Molecular Medicine	Oslo, Norway
Laboratory technician	2022-2024
Project: "Caretaker of the fish facility"	
KTH Royal Institute of Technology	Stockholm, Sweden
Postdoctoral researcher	2022-2024
Project: "Forcefields for electrochemistry in metal-organic frameworks"	
Project: "Reaction mechanisms of enantioselective hydrogenation of olefines"	
Nordic Consortium for CO ₂ Conversion	Scandinavia
Postdoctoral researcher	2022-2024
Project: "Modelling of CO2 electroreduction in metal-organic frameworks"	
PhD student	2018-2021
Project: "Rational catalyst design for the hydrogenation of CO ₂ derivates"	
Lecturer in	
Workshop in Microkinetic Modeling with COPASI	2022
Stockholm, Sweden. April 28-29	
Workshop in Microkinetic Modeling with COPASI	2019
Tromsø, Norway. March 26-27	

Internships	
Iceland University, Iceland	2022
Group of Egill Skúlason. Ab-initio molecular dynamics. November	
Valladolid University, Spain Group of Martin Jaraiz. Microkinetic modelling. June – July	2018
ICIQ, Spain	2015-2016
Group of Feliu Maseras. Modelling of single electron transfers.	
GMMF, Spain (Not paid) Group of E. Carolina Sañudo. Synthesis and characterization of magnetic	2014-2015 and fluorescent molecules.
Others	
Frenchie Bistro	Oslo, Norway
Waiter	Sept. 2021 – Feb. 2022
Skogstad Hotel ***	Hemsedal, Norway
Waiter and housekeeper	Summer. 2021
Hotel Port-Bó*** Receptionist	Palafrugell, Spain Summers 2013 – 2015
Hotel & Spa Mas de Torrent ****	
Receptionist	Torrent, Spain Summers 2009 – 2010
neseptionist	2411111213 2003 2010
Education	
Academic education	
Oslo University	Oslo, Norway
Ph.D. Chemistry Thesis: "Computational study on the deaminative hydrogenation of amid	2016-2021 les catalyzed by hase metal
complexes"	ies catalyzed by base metal
Rovira i Virgili University	Tarragona, Spain
M.Sc. Chemistry	2015-2016
Thesis: "Computational characterization of the mechanism of the reaction and aryl halides"	n between Fe(I) complexes
Barcelona University	Barcelona, Spain
B.Sc. Chemistry	2010-2015
Thesis: "Synthesis and characterization of coordination compounds with	-
Courses and Certifications	
Unsupervised Machine Learning Online. IBM course of >23h. June	2024
Supervised Machine Learning: Classification Online. IBM course of >24h. April	2024
Singularity workshop	2024
Stockholm, Sweden. February 12	
Supervised Machine Learning: Regression	2024

Online. IBM course of >20h. February

Exploratory Data Analysis for Machine LearningOnline. IBM course of >14h. December

2023

Introduction to GPUs course	2023
Stockholm, Sweden. October 12-13	
Alpha fold v2.0 and RoseTTAFold Workshop Online. Aug. 31-Sep. 1	2021
8 th MOLCAS Users' Workshop Uppsala, Sweden, Nov. 20-24	2017



Computational chemistry

Reaction mechanism exploration

Software: Gaussian, Jaguar (Schrodinger), COPASI, Acuchem

Rational catalyst design of organometallic catalysts.

Microkinetic modelling for the design and interpretation of experimental kinetic experiments and for the evaluation of theoretical models.

Drug discovery and material science

Software: Amber, Gromacs, CP2K

Forcefield parametrization of organometallic systems

Free energy calculations: FEP, EVB, umbrella sampling, metadynamics Properties calculations: binding energies, diffusion coefficients, viscosities...

Cheminformatics

Software: RDKit, OpenBabel, molSimplify

Automatic interpretation of chemical databases

Automatic generation of molecular structures for future processing (e.g. machine learning)

Others

Software: NBO6, NCIPLOT, OpenMolcas, Chemcraft, PHI, ioChem-BD

Experimental chemistry.....

Basic training in

Good laboratory practices, NMR, MS, UV-Vis, FT-IR, Spectrofluorometry, HPLC, GC and SQUID.

Informatics.....

I have worked with supercomputers and computer clusters for eight years, at a user level.

I am comfortable with python, and have basic knowledge of C++, Fortran, bash, awk and seq.

The python libraries I use most are os, sys, shutil, pandas, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, seaborn, sklearn, rdkit, molSimplify and OpenBabel.

Most of my programming has been scripting for workflow automation or data analysis.

I have recently started studying machine learning. So far, I have completed IBM online courses on "Exploratory Data Analysis" and "Machine Learning regression models".



Seven articles published in scientific journals. H index of five. Cited more than a hundred times. Five first-authorships.